Sanath Katakam

Cloud Developer / Full Stack Developer

Hyderabad, India

+91 8754551263

katakam.sanath@gmail.com
in linkedin.com/in/sanathkatakam/

github.com/sanathkatakam

Summary

Innovative, task-driven professional having around 4 years of experience in full stack development on cloud platform overseeing all aspects of SDLC, from analysis and design through execution and maintenance across diverse industries.

Skills

Azure Functions, Logic Apps, Service Bus, Azure SQL, Storage Accounts, Azure Automation, App Insights, ARM Templates, Container Registry, Angular, JavaScript, jQuery, Open Layers, .NET Core, .NET Framework, SQL Server, Azure Pipelines, Docker, Git, GitHub

Work Experience

Cloud Developer May 2021 - Present

Cognizant

Azure Integration

• Implement complex, high-quality, scalable, and extendable end-to-end solutions using Azure Serverless & .NET Core.

Environment: C#, .NET 5, Azure Functions, Logic Apps, Service Bus, Azure SQL, Azure Automation, GitHub, VS Code.

- Built integration solution to connect SAP and Salesforce system to reduce the manual effort of migrating 20+ Lakhs of Master-Detail data in Real-Time.
- Developed logic apps to read messages from source and Implemented functions using Service Bus and HTTP triggers to transform XML Data by applying business logic and posting it to destination.
- Designed and developed database schema using Azure SQL Server to store transactional data and implemented Runbooks using Azure Automation to delete aged data.
- Implemented Microservices Architecture by using Kong API Gateway.
- Containerized Azure Functions using Azure Container Registry.
- Prepared ARM Templates for deployment.

Full Stack Developer

Nov 2020 - May 2021

Arcadis

Railway Structure Designing Application

- Developed a data-driven application to design/modify the structures of railway tracks, track assets, and other manual efforts using a web application.
- Built scalable RESTful GeoJSON APIs and Visualized geographical data using Open Layers.
- Created a web application that can render rail structures dynamically and implemented features to edit, add & delete.
- Managed spatial data using SQL server.
- Built the CI/CD pipelines from scratch by using Azure Pipelines.

Environment: Kendo UI, .NET Core, Open Layers, MS SQL Server, Azure Web Apps, GitHub, Visual Studio.

Full Stack Developer Mar 2018 - Nov 2020

Accenture

Blend Factor

- Design, develop, and maintain applications using a wide range of technologies from .NET MVC to WebAPI and Angular to effectively
 solve business problems and Upgrade legacy systems to the latest versions.
- The primary role is to develop a real-time dashboard to track the blending factor of the multiple crushers in mines by using IOT & Grafana Dashboards.
- Fetched the data from the source system into a database by using F#.
- Wrote T-SQL queries to fetch data from the database and visualize it on a dashboard.

Environment: Grafana, F#, MS SQL Server, GitHub, Visual Studio.

Education

B. Tech 2013 - 2017

SRM University, Chennai